[Music]
hi hi and welcome to living in Central
Texas I'm Andrea dudic realtor and
Associate broker with vist real estate
now if you're moving to Central Texas
particularly the area of Bell County
maybe Temple belon Salo colen Fort
Cavazos or any of the nearly surrounding
areas you'll definitely want to watch
this video as I'll be giving a map tour
of belon Texas specifically but we'll be
touching on and a lot of the neighboring
areas there will be a ton of helpful
information in here I hope that it's
helpful to you and let's go ahead and
dive in okay so here we are taking a
look at Texas in
general and Central Texas is comprised
of quite a few counties belon is where
I've placed this little heart
here which Central Texas is going to
Encompass the Austin Round Rock
area over here to College
Station I'm freehanding this bear with
me
wakeo out here to
clean oh I don't know burnet's in there
kind of kind of somewhere in there and
Belton is about 1 hour north of Austin
60 m
really straight shot down 35 much easier
route
going away from Austin then into Austin
uh in terms of traffic and then you are
roughly 40 minutes south of
Waco 40 Mish and about 2 hours from the
Dallas Fort Worth
area so what's really neat is belon has
a small town feel we have a lot of
amenities here but we're not far away in
my opinion uh we're not far away from
bigger cities if you want to go do
really fun things in those areas now in
terms of beaches you're not really that
far out either so a lot of people
here when they go to
beaches I think they really enjoy Corpus
chrisy you're about 4 hours 260 miles
away from
there
galeston about 4
hours and then I spent a lot of time
growing up in South Padre Island with my
family it's actually one of the reasons
I moved here because I had such awesome
memories of living there South Padre
Island is down here at the bottom kind
of down herish
and South Padre Island is about 6 and
1/2 hours 400ish miles away from belon
now I go into Austin actually when I for
shopping I actually think the best malls
closest is here in Round
Rock but Austin has so much to do too so
we might do overnight stays there me and
my husband might um go to The Domain
they have a ton of shopping there you
could go to downtown Austin of course
there's just so much entertainment
right but let's zoom on
into belon okay so belon is right here
close to where I put that little heart
just below it and I've gone ahead and
outlined here Bell County so belon is
part of Bell County I do a lot of real
estaing in this area
particularly um because really it's
nothing nothing's really that far from
somewhere in Bell County so you've got
Troy over here um which is really close
to McGregor and McGregor is uh we now
have space X there Little River Academy
small cute little town there's actually
not a lot of inventory there often
people seem to want to move there and
never move away it's so cute Theo right
here is very very popular right now um
you know the closer that you get to
Austin the higher the price per square
foot and so the closer you get to Temple
Bon um the more affordable I think
houses will be really we get a lot of
people moving here for uh pcsing here um
being stationed at Fort Cavazos
interestingly enough Fort Cavazos is the
third largest military station in the
world and therefore we have a lot of
people being stationed
there when I get people reaching out to
move there um they frequently are
looking at
Colleen
Nolanville
belon Copper's Cove out here Temple m
maybe but from Fort Cavazos
to belon you're looking at a 25-minute
drive down
14 so you have the 14 that runs This
Way east to west and then we have the 35
coming all the way down you have the 95
moving through
here 36 takes you through G
Gatesville through
Temple so in addition to people moving
here from military why else might people
be moving here well it is much more
affordable than living in Austin and so
people are kind of migrating up this way
um we have umhb the University of Mary
Harden Baylor here
umhb and interestingly enough
we are a huge medical
Hub so we have a ton of
residents um for Scott and White so
Scott and White Baylor Scott and White
is the largest not for-profit Health
Care system in Texas and one of the
largest in the US so as you can see on
the
map this is Baylor Scott and White all
these little red dots so right here we
have Baylor Scott and White children's
mlan Children's Hospital we also have
Baylor Scott and White the main main
hospital the adult
hospital had both of my daughters there
so there's a lot of reasons that people
are moving here and there's um a lot of
over overlap between belon and Temple in
fact part of um Temple is Belton ISD and
so when people are moving here and they
say say they want to want to live in
belon I say well is that because you
just like that area or you want to be
part of that school district because we
don't want to roll out some of Temple if
that's the case so there's a lot of
overlap between those two as well as
overlap in um Morgan's Morgan's Point
Resort right here Morgan's Point is
super awesome I don't know why I think
this is so cool I'm originally from Las
Vegas but if you live in Morgan's Point
deer wander the neighborhood
and I don't know I just think that's
really neat um but there's a lot of
connectedness to Nature Morgan's Point
you're you know along the lake here like
belon
Lake and really no matter where you're
at in this area you are close to
Stillhouse Hollow Lake as well as belon
Lake um so there's ton of hiking here
CHD Falls Park Dana Peak Park all around
belon Lake
and let's look at belon so belon in and
of itself this is directly from belon
texas.gov really helpful resource if you
want to learn about
belon population of course this is as as
of 2020 so a little dated uh population
of 23,000 but again lots of overlaps
with those other areas that's more of
just built-in
proper and then we have locations and
distance to these other popular areas
but again lot of helpful resources and
information about belon Texas here we
zoom into belon you have 35 that runs
through
here so again you're coming up from
Austin you pass C you have
belon you can take 35 and grow through
temple on up to Waco you have
bies again if you're headed out to Fort
this
maybe let's talk about kind of like the
main routes through belon so
317 runs directly through belon it's
kind of the main street of belon there's
a lot on there and it's a lot of it's a
main segue to things all the things so
you have mlan children's hospital Baylor
Scott and White main hospital both
probably within 15 minutes of
belon maybe 25 if you're tucked away a
little more in Morgan's Point or on the
outer skirts
of belon let's take a look at downtown
belon so just off
of 14 and
35 right in
here we are going to have downtown belon
really cool stuff down here so right
here we have the Jin at Nolan Creek
which is on Nolan Creek and this spot is
so awesome it's a little venue if you
want to host weddings baby showers
special events you name
it and if you eat at the gym it
overlooks the creek and during the
summer you'll see um family kids whoever
um playing in the creek and it's really
beautiful and very relaxing you can sit
on the patio have cocktails s have food
they have scores
Pizza um Coronas Mexican food a little
ice cream joint I think there's a cigar
bar down there and you have oh my gosh
the I love breakfast food love breakfast
food and right here you have Water
Street Waffle
Company they have the best waffles a lot
of chicken and waffle style um they have
a lemon blueberry waffle
Skillets omelets awesome highly
recommend if you're down there we also
have Miller Smokehouse fantastic
barbecue
food oh nunas right here Thai
food um their eggplant Tower and their
chicken Pad Thai top two favorites so
good I think this is um ARA's coffee
I will be doing another video on that
coming up really cool little Coffee Spot
okay let's go ahead and look at the
terrain view I think this would be more
helpful again so that's the Water Street
Waffle Company we have the Bell County
Courthouse right down
here this is the Gin at Nolan Creek that
I was talking
about right
here Main Street so you have the Bell
County
Courthouse right here on this little
strip right here at these buildings this
is Beautiful Salon I've been going there
for years um Aly a beautiful Salon love
her Woodhouse Day Spa they are fantastic
so you can get your facials
massages waxing that's all down
there some
shops Bridal Shop we have the Sheriff's
Office Texas is really interesting uh I
don't again I'm from Las Vegas and so it
was a it was much different actually
there with houses and residential where
I was from you know houses were very
similar in a in a particular area here
um you know you can have a $200,000 home
next to a million doll
home and so and there's little pockets
of subdivisions of course but not
everywhere is the same actually while
we're on still on downtown let's back up
a little bit Miller Smokehouse there's
Chef's
barbecue
awesome but there are a lot of cute
little Nifty shops down there um but if
you're looking to maybe live in this
area there
are very a lot of established
neighborhoods in
downtown so a lot of these areas are
really established
if we stay on Main Street and move our
way
up and just Main Street turns into
[Music]
317 and there is your HB major grocery
store HB is so awesome they have I I
don't think they're just local to Texas
but um I hadn't been to them before PRI
of moving here and they are fantastic so
they have H B for your grocery you also
have Walmart across the
street bunch of little pocket
restaurants in there this Happy Teriyaki
enroll place right
here so good it's uh Korean barbecue
there's also a sweet rolled
tacos right here in the hvv parking lot
right here and it's fancy rolled ice
cream but everything you need is going
to be here there's also off of West
Adams which I'll show you here in a
minute and you can just hop on over to
Temple and Temple is going to be where
we have your target Best Buy
Ulta Ross Marshalls Olive
Garden BJ's Brew
House Home Depot and quite a few other
places that we'll go over but your fun
you know you have your shopping
there you have have 1 2 3 4 Walmarts
within a 20 minute
radius one to three
HBS now something that I think is really
important to note about belon um or just
living in Central Texas in general is
the property taxes so our houses our our
home prices here are a lot more
affordable than other areas but we have
really high property taxes and so if I'm
if I speak with you or if you're looking
here you want to make sure that you're
taking that into consideration when
purchasing because that's going to
affect your monthly payment now a really
awesome resource for that is bellcad
right here so you can go to bellcad.org
and right here you can go to property
search and you can type in an address
and see the property tax rate so if
you've got
a do a little math here so for example
let's just say you have a $300,000
home and the tax rate is
2.25 you're looking at 6750 annually in
just property taxes now of course there
are exemptions and things that you can
do to try and get that number down a
little bit but that is going to affect
your monthly payment but this is an
awesome resource to go to to find out
more information on
that now
every area is a little bit different on
property taxes I would say in general
you will see like within City Limits
probably 2.25 to
2.6 is in property taxes and then um 1.6
out you know 1.6 to 1.9 outside of City
Limits again that's not across the board
but outside of City Limits you are going
to not have those city taxes so you'll
save some money there
we go back to our map here one of my
favorite things to do in the area is go
to Dead Fish
Grill right here it overlooks beltin
Lake they have an outdoor patio it's a
seafood restaurant they also have
chicken and pasta and some other things
like that but it overlooks the lake and
you can sit on the patio they have the
best
margarita ever dead fish what's it DFG
Margarita super good
let me know if you try
it and so if you're looking to live near
the lake there are some options still in
building there there are individual lots
for sale there's also one or two
communities that have lots for sale can
I'd be happy to speak with you about
that okay but if we go back to
belon our little outline of belon you're
within Belton ISD now if you go to B
sd.net you can find all the information
on belon schools North Belton Middle
School pural Elementary School South
belon Middle School Tarver Elementary
Lakewood Elementary belon High School if
you click on that you can get specific
information for those schools okay so
what I really want to do is show you
homes in belon
so I pulled up the my MLS the multiple
listing service which is going going to
show me all homes for sale in belon so I
searched any home in belon um the city
of
belon
236 listings and actually if I go ahead
and
add Morgan's
Point okay not a ton more
but these are all everything we have
sort of near the
lake in terms of belon actually let's
look at statistics so Bell County in
general that belon falls into has a
median home price of
284,000 and here you can see the percent
percentages that the home prices fall
into so 200 to 300,000 is 46% of that
another about quarter falls into the 300
to
400,000 and then the last just under 20%
Falls between 400 and a
million but in terms of belon median
price 280 bulk of our listings fall in
that $200 to $300,000 price point a
third fall into 300 to
400,000 and then just a small percentage
above that those are your average
numbers but there's a lot of
inventory and a lot of homes to look at
and a lot of homes to pick
from I was telling you there's a wide
variety in home prices as I hover over
these you see we have
7,2 million next to
$218,000 home so you have plenty of area
to pick from whether you're looking for
a more established home or a newer home
now if you're curious about traffic you
can go over to layers here on Google
Maps and hit
traffic so we must be having a little
accident or something here today cuz
this is not
normal but typically there is not a lot
of traffic the most traffic you're going
to see is going to be on
35 often um and then kind of the main
streets through so Main Street 317 West
Adams which that's a really big one too
we're going to zoom in so again belon
317 runs through zoom in now as you go
up 317 you're going to hit West Adams
this is the other Main Street
intersection through belon so if you
want to be close to
that's another good place um you come in
here zoom in West Adams and it
goes east to west
3177 east east on
Adams you have soul Garden another
Korean barbecue so this strip right here
as we zoom in was hit by the tornado in
May including my
office back here and they've rebuilt
Community is awesome really pulled
together
but you have a ton of food down here a
lot of churches in this area we have two
chick-fil-et three Chick-fil-A in Temple
Belton there's one right there you have
soul Garden you have Rock and ramen
which is
ramen Pat Creek Burger this is another
Walmart as we continue down Adams so
this area right
here
is these areas right here they are newer
homes more established than that last I
don't know 15 years or so again more
food up here Panda Smoky Mo barbecue
lots of coffee you have Dutch Brothers
um across the street you have Starbucks
right here um summer Moon I'm doing
another in my coffee video I'll be going
over summer Moon as well they're in this
little area that little shopping plaza
you have wildf flower Country Club so
come down Adams here
and you're going to connect
to Southwest HK Dodge and loop
363 and you have the Wildflower Country
Club right here and so if you want to
live on the golf course or near the golf
course there you
go spare time bowling arcade and as we
start to zoom out so as you go down West
Adams you're going to be into Temple
right so belon
is there and then we kind of were over
here so again if you're thinking about
moving to the belon area I recommend
considering or
exploring some of these other
areas some of
the um more affordable or lower priced
homes priced per square foot um or
overall price Little River
Academy Troy so Temple belon are going
to be slightly more expensive in theory
than some of these outskirt areas and if
you start looking in these outskirt
areas just outside of Temple Belton
you'll start to get more land and larger
larger size Lots so if you want more
space um larger larger yards more
privacy you're going to want to look in
those surrounding
areas but there are a couple communities
in Temple Belton that have um walking
trails that's going to
be Dawson's
Ranch rot Oaks and Three Creeks this is
a really awesome Community to check out
if you enjoy outdoor activities as I
said they have um walking trails
throughout but they're going to be right
around here Three Creeks and there are a
lot of new construction homes you have
KS stylecraft Omega tip
it maybe a couple smaller builders in
there but you're minutes away from the
leg you have uh you're about 18 minutes
20 minutes from Fort Cavazos another 20
minutes if you're working at the
hospital really easy access to 14 and
down 317 so that is a hot one if I have
people moving here that want really
great and easy access but also want to
have some of those amenities so all in
all belon is a really cool place to be I
love living here and I hope that there
was some really great information here
for
you um if you'd like more information on
belon or help with moving to the area
you can find all my contact information
below I'd love to speak with you um
until next time now if you like this
video I have two others currently um
that you may want to check out one is a
$799,000 luxury Custom home build in
Morgan's Point and the other is a Custom
home build in Temple Texas within Valor
States both are awesome go check them
out and until next time